[engine starts, revving]
[Jerry] This is a 1952 VW Bug
in azure blue.
It has a four-cylinder,
25-horsepower engine.
It's called a split-window
because the rear window was made
in two pieces to save money.
And if, like me, you feel that true
humility is always in short supply,
this is the car for you.
[telephone ringing]
[Larry] This is Larry speaking.
-[Jerry] Hey, man.
-[Larry] Hey.
-[Jerry] Wanna do something?
-[Larry] Absolutely.
[Jerry] Really? You free?
[Larry] Uh... Yeah, I can be free.
-[Jerry] Wanna grab a quick coffee?
-[Larry] Let's get some coffee.
[Jerry] Hi, I'm Jerry Seinfeld,
and this is
Comedians in Cars Getting Coffee.
Today my guest is Larry David.
Larry and I have been friends
for over 30 years.
And we did a TV series
together in the '90s.
What the hell, man?
[Jerry]
Do you still rely on baseball as a...
What's the word, uh...
Is it a palliative?
Can I use that word?
Is baseball a palliative in your life?
By the way, fantastic word.
I've never heard it come out
of a human's mouth in my life.
[upbeat music playing]
I always loved this car.
-Really?
-Always.
You excited?
I wouldn't say I'm excited,
but I'm looking forward to it.
My mother used to say to me once a week,
"Larry, why can't you get excited
about something?
You're never excited.
Nothing excites you.
We're going to the Irvington Hotel
in New Jersey.
They have ice skating there."
"No, I'm not excited."
You know what's one of your
great theories?
-Each generation gets better looking.
-Yes, yes.
Yeah, that's really good,
observant and original thinking.
It's a miracle we ever got any work done
because nobody can waste time
like you and me.
-Well, it is--
-Just waste it.
-It is a miracle, I agree.
-It's a miracle.
[Jerry] One of the things that the
comedian mind-set requires is laziness.
[Larry] Absolutely.
-You don't wanna do real work.
-No, no.
I was always... I always wanted the show
to get canceled, so I didn't have to work.
[upbeat music playing]
How about this experience?
You're having a different experience.
I am having a different experience.
That's for sure.
[Larry] I remember the thing
about this car,
everybody said,
"You can't get in an accident with it."
[Jerry] I'll avoid that.
-Everybody in college had this car.
-Yeah, yeah.
[Jerry] But how about that view down
to the road?
That's what I love.
-[Jerry] You see the road so well.
-[Larry] You do.
I don't like the, uh...
I don't like driving a stick.
That was very Jewish.
Well, I'm Jewish.
And you know what?
I could be described as very Jewish.
[Jerry] Gotta turn on the wipers.
Watch this.
[Larry] Yeah.
-[Larry] Holy cow.
-[Jerry] Isn't that hilarious?
[Larry] You have no interest in driving
a '52 Hudson or something like that?
[Jerry] No, too big.
I like cars that feel like toys.
-I was looking to buy one.
-Really?
-Yeah.
-When was this?
-This was like five years ago. Yeah.
-Five years ago.
-Knew it was five years ago.
-Yeah. [snorts]
-It's always five years ago.
The lunch at a normal American restaurant
is very problematic for me.
-Piece of fish? Salad?
-I don't like to have hot food for lunch.
-Yeah, a salad, but...
-Yeah.
-There's not much in the salad.
-What do you love?
-For lunch?
-Yeah.
I'll usually have a salad for lunch.
-But then I have a protein shake.
-Wow.
And where do you get that?
Get it in a store.
Yeah.
The answer was equally
as stupid as the question.
[Jerry] I don't understand
that there's nothing you can eat.
[Larry] People are disturbed by it.
My ex-wife hated it.
I think that's one of the reasons
our marriage ended.
She couldn't take the way you eat?
You know,
because I stopped drinking coffee.
Right.
And she hated it.
I said, "What do you care?"
-I had tea in the cup.
-Yeah.
She said, "We can't even share
a coffee in the morning anymore."
I said, "But there's something in my cup.
You can't see into my cup.
I'm still sipping,
there's still steam coming out of it."
-Right. I know.
-"What's the difference?"
I ordered soup the other day.
Somebody said,
"That's all you're gonna get?"
"What the hell do you care?"
[both laughing]
[Jerry] I always think the people
in the restaurant
always look like that restaurant.
Whatever the style of the restaurant is,
the people look like that style,
that's why they go there.
Any restaurant you go to,
if the people in there
are dressing in these muted tones
like you like...
taupes, bones...
-beiges...
-I, I don't...
...soft grays.
-I don't think so.
-No?
I've evolved, clothing wise...
-You have?
-...since the days I think.
I know you're still with
the very soft shoulder.
-You don't like a constructive shoulder.
-No. Never liked that shoulder.
Yeah. It is amazing
how we got any work done.
I agree.
[Jerry] Okay, I wanna stop
in front of this car here.
This is a Bugatti. That's a bee car.
That's-- A bee would drive that car.
And, you know, VW makes Bugattis.
So these two cars were made
by the same company at different times.
Wow.
[Jerry] By the way, this Bugatti
has 10 radiators, my car doesn't have any.
All right, let's go eat.
But look at the turn signal.
-Holy mackerel!
-[Jerry] It's called a semaphore.
[Larry] I thought a semaphore
was some grammatical notation.
-That's a semicolon.
-I'm gonna look that up.
[Larry] You just made the distance
that was acceptable
for me to hold that door.
[Jerry] Thank you.
[upbeat music playing]
-I would like a cup of coffee.
-I'll have an herbal tea.
Do you remember those
bowls of cereal I used to eat?
-You still do that?
-No.
When did this happen?
-Five years ago?
-Some years ago. Five...
Hey, look. I've got it in a cup.
You don't know what it is.
Well, bully for you.
And so if this is tea rather than coffee,
a person should find that so disturbing?
I'm sorry that you're not gonna like
what I'm about to say,
but I'm afraid your wife
has a bit of a point.
-Really?
-Yes.
There's a point? Look, I can talk
just as well holding this cup
as if there were coffee in it.
What's the difference?
-Wanna know the difference?
-I do.
We go to an ice cream shop, I get a cone.
And you get a salad.
That's the difference.
And you go,
"What? I'm eating, you're eating."
It's the mood.
Who could say what creates mood?
Mood is a thing that's just there.
The only reason we know it's there
is that we feel it.
You're giving me a scientific argument
that I can't combat.
-What's funny about that?
-I don't know.
[Jerry] What is the situation
that you're in
where you just start eating things
that you would not normally eat?
I'll be at a dinner party, okay?
They're serving, let's say, chicken, okay?
-Ordinarily, I won't eat chicken.
-What the hell is wrong with chicken?
It's a lot of cholesterol.
-Chicken?
-Yeah.
And if it's not free-range chicken,
there's a lot wrong with it.
How much do you think
these chickens really enjoy that range?
You think they're going out there
like a palomino?
I think they're enjoying it a lot more
than that little cage
where they're [beep] on each other.
-A little scary.
-It's not like a range,
like Monument Valley, John Wayne.
They're not out on the range,
you know, just...
"What do you say
we can head out onto the range?"
-You're looking at it...
-Yeah.
-That kind of range.
-"Home on the Range." That range.
-Yeah, yeah.
Most people would say, dietarily...
-you're a master.
-I'm not a master.
-No?
-No. I have snacking problems.
-Oh, really?
-Yeah.
-Give me the circumstances--
-When do I go off?
When you go off.
Give me "Larry David in the debauched...
-The debauched..."
-[sputters]
-Oh, Jesus.
-Why do you love that word?
-I don't know. It's a funny word.
-It's a funny word.
What's that guy's name?
What's the Penthouse guy?
-Bob Guccione.
-It's a Bob Guccione word.
"You know, a lot of people think
there's just debauchery going..."
A real spit-take is not often.
You don't get that often, right?
-Probably five years since I've seen one.
-Yeah.
All right, so when am I
gonna let my guard down?
When am I gonna eat like a human?
When do you go out of control?
Out of control is two pieces of pizza.
-Right?
-Right.
Never two.
-Never two?
-No.
I'll have six if I want.
When I decide to go, when I pull that pin
and I throw that grenade...
Me out of control,
it's half a bag of raw cashews.
Oh, boy.
I have this pitch that I've never done
about what my social life was like
before Seinfeld,
and something about how, um...
I was very desperate,
and yet I was also very particular.
You know...
which is a very odd combination.
Even Quasimodo,
the Hunchback of Notre-Dame,
he had to have the best-looking girl
in the village, you know.
And his friends would try to fix him up,
they go,
"No, Quasi, there's a girl in my office.
I, I, I think you should meet her."
"Is she good looking?"
[waitress speaking indistinctly]
[Jerry] Want any of this?
Look how beautiful that is.
All right, I'll taste it.
Great.
[Jerry] I cannot wait to see the look
on your face when you eat this pancake.
Here, put a little syrup on there.
This is gonna be great.
I can't wait for this.
Oh, am I excited now.
Larry David is gonna eat a pancake.
I can't believe this is how people live,
that people can do this all the time.
Yes.
[upbeat music playing]
But don't you think once it cools off,
it loses its allure?
The pancake?
Don't you think the heat
is like a big part of it?
-Yeah.
-I'm kind of intrigued by that.
Heat doesn't have any flavor.
-It's inviting.
-Why? What does it do?
It warms you.
That's very Kramer-ish.
"It's good, Jerry. Heat, it warms you."
When I think back on the show,
you would pitch me some premise,
some insane, absurd thing,
and I would just go, "Okay."
-Right. Yeah.
-And you would just crack up.
Okay, yeah.
'Cause it's something
I won't even tell another soul.
And now we're gonna do it on TV.
You would have a cigar after lunch,
remember that?
-Right in the office, right?
-Yes.
And you would offer sage advice.
You seemed like, "Yes, come, my child.
I've got this all figured out."
Anything you say with a cigar
just sounds so much better.
It imbues you with knowledge.
What is it about it?
There's something contemplative about it.
-Why not a cigarette?
-A cigarette isn't contemplative.
It's not that...
A cigarette... Is that.
-Right.
-It's anxiety.
There's anxiety associated with it.
-You know what I mean?
-Right.
Whereas the cigar is relaxing.
And when you relax,
you're open to more thoughts.
You have time to think.
A cigar takes time.
-A cigar takes time.
-That's the key to it.
That's the whole key.
Someone smoking a cigar is in no hurry.
-Absolutely, you're in no hurry at all.
-Right.
-Whereas the cigarette smoker, rushed.
-Yeah.
Gotta get out, you know.
-But a cigarette takes some time.
-Yes, I know, but...
A cigarette is just, it's just...
It's not something you're enjoying.
Oh, right. You continue to have
one of the finest minds I've ever met.
Coming from you,
I take that as a great compliment.
From day one,
"This guy's got some head on him."
That cigar-cigarette thing, I love that.
Here's an analysis of something
by two idiots
that no one else is doing.
You have finally done
the show about nothing.
-Here's your change. Thank you.
-Thank you.
Okay, it's $41.
What's your tip?
What's, what's your tip policy in general?
Exorbitant.
And if I may say, tip anxiety.
I think it's a Jewish thing.
I used to do that bit on that.
Representing the tribe, in a way.
And, and, and it's...
You need to leave decent amounts
so they don't think you're a cheap Jim.
Then, you know, you can't give too much...
'cause then you don't want them to think
you're a showy Jim.
There's that, too.
You gotta straddle the line.
'Cause they'll get you on
either end of this.
You know, you come in with a cigar...
and act all...
[speaking indistinctly]
Now you're fleshing it up quite a bit.
The waiter or waitress
would look at a big tip
and not be pleased?
How can that happen?
If they're already an anti-Semite.
-Oh, I see.
-Yeah.
-Wanna throw it in here?
-I'll open it.
-Really? No, you don't have to.
I like to open a dumpster.
Larry Miller used to do a funny thing
about, people would say,
"He's really gay."
You know, what does that mean?
So, does he enjoy it
more than the other guys? Or...
I, I... It means that...
he behaves in a way that one, one would...
perceive him to be gay more readily
than another person.
All right, thank you for clearing that up.
Yep.
What kind of underwear do you wear?
I'm still briefs.
-Really?
-Yep.
-Briefs over 60.
-Yes. I couldn't make the transition.
Well, now they have a thing called
the boxer brief, which is what I wear.
Yeah?
Which is a brief
that has a little leg to it.
Uh-huh.
And it's very nice when that's all you...
Around the house, you know.
You feel comfortable
going from the bedroom
-to the kitchen in the boxer brief.
-Uh-huh.
-Whereas you may not...
-Oh, no, I--
-Do you parade at all?
-No, you cannot parade with briefs.
Yeah.
Does it say on the box?
Is there a little parade
with a line through it?
"Do not parade."
[Jerry laughing]
-"Caution."
-"Parading is not recommended..."
-"In this garment."
[both laughing]